<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on IDerr</title><link>https://iderr.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on IDerr</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iderr.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploy your kubernetes as a service using Kubermatic ! Part 2</title><link>https://iderr.github.io/p/deploy-your-kubernetes-as-a-service-using-kubermatic-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iderr.github.io/p/deploy-your-kubernetes-as-a-service-using-kubermatic-part-2/</guid><description>Introduction In the last article, we saw the global architecture of Kubermatic, we will now deploy it on a single kubernetes cluster using Helm, without deploying all the stuff required by Kubermatic team
Prerequisites A storage class named kubermatic-fast A kubernetes cluster for managing kubermatic and seed clusters</description></item><item><title>Deploy your kubernetes as a service using Kubermatic ! Part 1</title><link>https://iderr.github.io/p/deploy-your-kubernetes-as-a-service-using-kubermatic-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iderr.github.io/p/deploy-your-kubernetes-as-a-service-using-kubermatic-part-1/</guid><description>Introduction Want to build your own EKS, GKE on vanilla Kubernetes ? Here&amp;rsquo;s an easy way to use Kubermatic as your kubernetes provider on your infra.
Kubermatic will manage all your kubernetes clusters using your favorite hypervisor, with a great multi-tenant UI.
Prerequisites To make your own Kubernetes as a Service you need :
At least one kubernetes cluster, will be used to host control plane services and kubermatic software</description></item><item><title>Week 2 - Using Hasura to analyze OpenFoodFacts</title><link>https://iderr.github.io/p/week-2-using-hasura-to-analyze-openfoodfacts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iderr.github.io/p/week-2-using-hasura-to-analyze-openfoodfacts/</guid><description>Introduction In the last article, we have imported OpenFoodFacts data from a CSV format to PostgreSQL.
Now, our data is ready to be analysed by anyone. SQL can be great for analysis but if we want to build an application, we&amp;rsquo;ll need another transport layer like REST or GraphQL. So in this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how create a quick GraphQL API using Hasura
You can find all my work on my Github : https://github.</description></item><item><title>Week 1 - New project on OpenFoodFacts</title><link>https://iderr.github.io/p/week-1-new-project-on-openfoodfacts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iderr.github.io/p/week-1-new-project-on-openfoodfacts/</guid><description>Introduction Today we will discuss how to import OpenFoodFacts data from their CSV to a PostgreSQL Database.
I wanted to work on OpenFoodFacts data, but never found MongoDB really great to work with, so I decided to migrate the CSV Data to Postgres, and clean the database (and give back a bit to this awesome community)
You can find all my work on my Github : https://github.com/IDerr/Openfoodfacts
How to download OpenFoodFacts data OpenFoodFacts provides all their data for free on their website, with three different formats: Json (based on their mongodb database), CSV and RDF You can download al the data on their website: https://openfoodfacts.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Tutor</title><link>https://iderr.github.io/p/introduction-to-tutor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iderr.github.io/p/introduction-to-tutor/</guid><description>Introduction Today, we will discuss how to use Tutor for deploying OpenEdx. OpenEdx is a platform used to deploy your courses online, it&amp;rsquo;s an Udemy like but self hosted.
Tutor is an amazing tool to get it deployed with Docker (or Kubernetes).
Installation Tutor installation Installation is really straightforward, a simple binary to download and you&amp;rsquo;re done !
sudo curl -L &amp;#34;https://github.com/overhangio/tutor/releases/download/v12.1.6/tutor-$(uname -s)_$(uname -m)&amp;#34; -o /usr/local/bin/tutor sudo chmod 0755 /usr/local/bin/tutor Shamefully copied/pasted from the documentation</description></item><item><title>OVH provider for cert-manager DNS-01</title><link>https://iderr.github.io/p/ovh-provider-for-cert-manager-dns-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iderr.github.io/p/ovh-provider-for-cert-manager-dns-01/</guid><description>Introduction First article of this new blog!
Today we will discuss how to configure automatic Let’s-Encrypt certificate renewal with a domain hosted in OVH.
I have not found a clear tutorial on how to setup a cluster wide OVH cert-manager provider so there it is.
Installation Cert-manager installation Quick reminder, installing cert-manager is pretty straightforward with Helm. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to replace the version with the latest one : https://github.com/jetstack/cert-manager/releases
kubectl create namespace cert-manager helm repo add jetstack https://charts.</description></item></channel></rss>